For the podcast, I've interviewed a
bunch of CTOs and distinguished
engineers from companies like Enthropic,
Google, and Meta. And my favorite
question to ask these people is if they
could go back to the beginning of their
career and [music] give themselves some
advice, what would it be? And this is my
favorite question to ask because these
people have so much experience. I'm
always curious, what is that thing that
they wish they knew earlier that we
could learn from? And so, before you do
any New Year's planning, I thought it
would be helpful if I curated all of the
top answers to that question. And so I
went through every single episode that
I've done so far and I watched the
answers to that question to pick the
ones that I felt were most authentic or
potentially helpful. And so this video
is a compilation of all the best answers
to that question. So here's the full
video. If you could go back to yourself
when you just entered the industry and
give yourself some advice, what would
you say?
>> I have a few thoughts that I share. One,
Roy Disney said decisions are easy when
your values are clear to you. Right?
Decisions for me a lot of times were
hard because I didn't have clear values.
If you know exactly where you're going,
decisions toward getting there become a
lot easier. So, one advice I would give
my younger self is spend a little more
time thinking about what you actually
want, right? Before you commit to doing
these things. I think another thing is I
often feel like I was the dog that
caught the car, you know, like I was
convinced when I joined Microsoft that
what I wanted to be was a dev manager.
Okay. And so for my first eight years or
so, I would take any job that would get
me a step toward that. So one decisions
were easy then because it was like,
well, does this job get me a step
closer? Yes, it does. Then I'll take it,
right? But once I caught that car, you
know, once I hit that level, once I
recognized that, hey, E7 might be my
terminal level. This might be the
highest I ever get in my career. Um, the
problem with peaking early, you know,
cuz I hit that level when I was
probably, I don't know, 20, you know, 30
years old or or something like this,
right? Um,
the problem is you're like a child
actor. Like the question is what are you
going to do with the rest of your life?
Like if your whole plan is acting and if
nobody hires you for acting, you're
going to be in a world of hurt, like
you're you are not going to enjoy the
next 40 years of work. And so for me, I
I was the dog that caught that car. And
I had no mental model for like once I
became the death manager, which I did
become right at a very young age. Once I
became a level 67 and I became that at a
relatively young age, it was sort of
like well
like what happens next? And I really
went through a period of pretty serious
depression because I felt like I had
lost a purpose to life. Like life seemed
to have so much meaning and direction
when I had a clear goal. But I caught
the car, right? And then it was like
what to do. So the other thing I would
caution my young self about is to just
be sure you actually want the thing you
want. You know what I mean? Like one
thing I tell people now is, you know,
would you want to be Warren Buffett? You
know, so many people love the billions
of dollars, but he also in his is in his
late 90s. Like, would you want a few
billion dollars and be in your late 90s?
Like, is that worth it? Is that what you
want? Like, this is an interesting
question, right? So, I think for me now,
I think a lot more about um am I even
going a direction I want to be at when I
get there? Right? One final thought that
I'll leave with you with the sleeping
bag business is sometimes you bend the
read, sometimes you break the read,
right? Sometimes things break and they
aren't fixable. So, when I had sleeping
bags in my office, uh my fiance came out
to Seattle to visit me. During that
time, when she visited me in Seattle
from Maryland, during that time, I would
see her every evening at 11:00 p.m. when
work ended. That was when I would go see
her. So, basically, I got to eat like a
late Denny's dinner with her from 11:00
p.m. to like midnight, and that was my
plan for my visiting fiance, right? I am
very fortunate and lucky that she is my
wife now. But anybody I tell that story
to, you could bet nine out of 10 times
that the story that ends with that's how
I got the engagement ring back, right?
Is how that story ends, right? I did not
realize that some reads bend and some
reads break. and I was clearly bending
something to an extreme that most things
would have broken, right? And so I do
think that in one's life, back to your
point of like what should a diehard
person who only cares about career do
like what is the absolute fastest way to
like get there, right? I would say a be
sure that's what you want, right? Don't
be the dog that caught that thing and
then you regret catching the thing,
right? So a be sure that's really what
you want. And part B is like,
you know, be sure you're com comfortable
with other things breaking, you know,
because like that is what it will take
to get there if that's truly what you
want. So my advice to my younger self
about that period of time would have
been, you know, in net getting to level
67, getting to an E7 when you're 30
versus 38 in the big arc doesn't make
any difference. Like beyond 38, I still
have 30 years of work to go, right? So
it's like how fast do I want to be at my
terminal level? Like what's the real
plan there versus can I keep a healthy
relationship with my spouse, with my
kids, right? That's important. And so
that's what I would advise back then.
Maybe saying something around people
pleasing, right? you know, in the the
culture that I was raised in and you
know, there are these tracks that you
get on and it's like, okay, we'll do
well in school and then go get a job and
then go get married and like, you know,
you have this feeling of being ahead or
behind, right? So, that relative
comparison. Um, but then also after you
do a thing, after you make some sort of
achievement, you're kind of looking for
to someone else for validation. I don't
know if my younger self would have like
listened to be quite honest with you,
but you know just if I could somehow
learn this lesson that like the person
that you really need to please is
yourself. Just being like are is are you
doing what you want to do? Are you doing
it because that's the expectation of
somebody else? Are you climbing the
ladder because you want to get to the
top or are you climbing a ladder because
the ladder was put in front of you? Just
examining that. I think to my younger
self, I would just tell him to trust
himself a little bit more because I
think for a very long time, I just had
so much imposter syndrome. I was so
anxious that
uh you know, I wasn't going to do so
well. And over time, I like built up
that confidence like through projects,
my projects succeeding and working well
with others and getting good feedback.
But I think I was like really unsure of
myself. And I actually feel like I could
have done more if I was willing to trust
my judgment a little bit more or have
more of almost like audacity to um push
the boundary and try new things. Uh
because a I had a lot of ideas that I
felt like I maybe waited a little bit
too long because you know I felt like oh
am I going to rock the boat too much but
um I ended up doing a lot of those
projects that did rock the boat and they
were very successful and I wish I just
you know trust myself a little bit more
to do it earlier so I'd be less anxious
and stressed all the time and be
fretting less over imposter syndrome in
the beginning of my career. I'm going to
I'm going to take a more maybe emotional
angle on this as opposed to technical or
career oriented, but like I think the
advice to me would be to really invest
in relationships and the aspects outside
of work. Like I'm only just now
realizing in the last year and a half or
so that like I was underinvested in in
friendships and romantic relationships
and things of this nature. And it was
largely because I was putting so much
effort into work even if it wasn't in
hours-wise like that's where my
optimizations were. and you realize that
like you spend all this time road
mapping, goaling, checking in with
yourself about your career progression.
But in terms of like general life
progression, I didn't apply nearly that
same figure. And so I think that that
had a negative consequence and only
moving to LA now 2 years ago did the
shift. And this is because I got pulled
out of the tech bubble. Now a lot of my
friends don't work in tech and we invest
a lot more in each other both
financially and from a time perspective.
And I have found that my life is so much
more fulfilled because of this. And so
work continues to be a focus. It
continues to grow. Things are great
there. But now like I have all these
people that I can rely on and like I'm
moving apartments right now and and I
have any number of people that I can
call to help me move. And these small
things are like, you know, like I said,
it's a bit sentimental, but they're
they're really what matter in life more
so than your quick career progression.
So I wish I had learned to more fairly
allocate time between those two and
effort. I would come back to the don't
be the best, be the only. Um, I I think
early in my career had a lot of fear of,
hey, I'm I'm mediocre at a lot of
things. Like I I see my friends I would
look up to my friends who are really
good at design and I' like, oh, I wish I
could do that, right? Or I look to my
other friends who are just better
engineers like I wish I could that could
do that. But the thing that I had was
ability to negotiate across all those
themes. And that's uncomfortable because
I wasn't sure if that would pan out. And
it turns out that it did. Um, and then
the other thing is exactly as we were
just discussed, don't like don't don't
filter, be be braver about this stuff.
Um, it's it's kind of ironic that later
in my career, I part of like my 9 to5
effectively became public speaking.
going through high school, I was deathly
afraid of public speaking.
I would run away from class to avoid it.
Right? Like I I vividly remember those
stories. And then it dawned on me later
when I was doing post rank that hey why
is it that I was even through university
like I had cold sweats standing out in
front of a class trying to explain the
thing. Uh but I was totally adept and
fine when I was pitching uh my product
to an audience. And the difference is in
one hand I I was trying to describe a
thing that you know I didn't have any
particular investment in it was a test
of my knowledge versus here's a thing
I'm passionate about and I want to like
enact change in the ecosystem to move it
to some new direction. So that turned
out to make all the difference for me
and uh maybe that's the key thing like
if you told me uh early in my college
career that my future holds public
speaking I would I don't know what I
would do. [laughter] I would say that
you're crazy.
>> So I'll answer in two ways. One of them
I did and one of them I really didn't.
The thing I would do is always prefer
high growth. My whole career was in
companies that were growing very
rapidly. And I compare that, people talk
about a career ladder. Well, my ladder
was always an escalator. I could climb,
but it was also moving up for me. And
so, the reason I got where I went is
because Amazon grew 100fold while I was
there from 10,000 people to a million.
Revenue grew like 80 times. The
escalator went up and I rode it. I also
climbed. So, that part I would keep the
same. The thing I would change is
probably not surprising you. I would
wake up much sooner to jobs are still
with other humans. It's great to be an
expert. It's great to be right, but
build the skills to have the
relationships, make the friends,
um, get to know lots of people.
And you don't have to be an extrovert to
do that. I was a classic introvert. I've
certainly learned to be more
extroverted, but with online tools like
LinkedIn or pick your tool, you can make
a reputation and build connections from
the safety of your keyboard in your
darkened room all by yourself. And so do
do whatever works for you, but get known
because it works so much better. You
know, Amazon called me for the job, not
the other way around. And you want that
happen. So build that reputation.
>> The thing I'll say is, "Hey Dwayne, I
know you like code in, but the thing you
should realize, right, is when someone
goes and tells you, hey, can you write
some code to do this?" You should stop
and think, how do they know that's the
right code to to write? You should aim
to be the person who's making those
decisions around what's the right thing
to do. And I feel if I had that earlier
on in my career, there's a lot of
imposttor syndrome and other stuff I
dealt with early in my career that
having this clarity is like, you know,
I'm more than what I can type on a
keyboard, right? My ideas and the value
I derive is is greater and like focus
not on being an output machine, but
really being the one and focus like can
I be in those rooms that's deciding
what's the right thing to do?
I'd probably say younger self, uh, be be
more courageous and less embarrassed.
You're going to fail a lot and it's
fine.
>> That's easier said than done. Like I
feel like embarrassment is like you just
feel it.
>> Yeah, I know. I mean, but this would be
the opening two sentences before a
larger conversation
about how to search your own feelings
and understand them. Uh, you know, maybe
it would actually be Brian, you should
go to therapy. That might also be good
advice. I think it's it's generally
helpful to uh to be more in touch with
your own emotions for your own sake and
it helps you relate with other people
better.
>> Go where you're valued. I've seen lots
of people go onto teams where they're
not valued.
>> You're really good at working on front
end, right? And then you end up on a
backend team and all of a sudden your
performance is crap. Or like you like
working on framework things and you're
on a product team and you're like
constantly tweaking frameworks and
making them better and then you get a
really bad rating at the end of the year
even though you landed like 500 diffs or
something.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Like go into the environment in which
like you're valued and maybe you end up
being an environment you're not valued
in for a year but just like recognize
that and get out of it.
>> Right.
>> Right. So I think
>> so like lean into your strengths
basically.
>> Yeah. You're you're trying to lean into
your strengths but the your management
chain or your team around you doesn't
care about your strengths. Right. go and
find a team that likes your strengths
and go there
>> and you're going to be way happier. It's
going to work much better for you.
>> Just try stuff and don't don't be afraid
just because it looks hard or because
those other people look much better than
you because they may might be better
than you. Sure. But but but you can also
get there. It's not rocket science. It
is just computers. And if you if you
like computers, you're pretty well off
if you just keep going with that.
>> Just use common sense. [laughter]
[gasps] I think there's a lot of stuff
in a especially in big companies that
pulls you away from common sense.
There's a lot of this like organia
things are this way because they have
been this way. There's a lot of
misaligned incentives. There's also a
lot of good things, but there's the
these things also. So, it it's just
really important to use common sense for
this. And you know, early on in my
career, I was kind of starting a bunch
of startups and worked at a lot of
startups. And I think there too, it's
the same thing. Kind of use common sense
to figure out what the market wants and
what users want to build it. So yeah,
just like trust yourself and and develop
your common sense. Thanks for listening
to the podcast. I don't sell anything or
do sponsorships, but if you want to help
out with the podcast, you can support by
engaging with the content on YouTube or
on Spotify if you want to drop a review,
that'll be super helpful. And if there's
any guests that you want to bring on to,
please let me know. I feel like sourcing
very senior IC's, there's no wellstudied
list out there on Google that I can just
search this up. So, if there's someone
in your org or at your company who you
really look up to and you want to hear
their career story, let me know and I'll
reach out to